Janmajay Singh

CONTACT Information

E-mail: janmajaysingh22@gmail.com Website: janmajaysingh.github.io Phone: (+81) 70-4112-0526

RESEARCH INTERESTS My research focuses on applications of A.I. in healthcare where I have worked at the intersection of predictive, causal and mixture models. I have conducted research in biomedical (DNA sequence, EMR, ECG), recommendation and NLP domains. My work has been featured in **JMIR Medical Informatics**, **UAI** and **RecSys**.

EDUCATION

SRM University, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Bachelors in Technology, Computer Science and Engineering (July 2013 - June 2017)

• CGPA: 9.4/10

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Massachusetts, USA

Special Student, Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (September 2015 - May 2016)

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Fujifilm Corp. - R&D HQ, Kaisei, Kanagawa, Japan

Researcher - Quantitative Biology

November, 2020 - Present

Part of the Liquid Biopsy team at the Imaging Technology Center. Primary responsibilities include predictive model design and development for cancer prediction from blood DNA samples. Secondary responsibilities include algorithm design to reduce noise from DNA sequencing process. Proposed noise reduction algorithm successfully reduced measurement noise by 57% compared to targeted 10%, substantially improving the project workflow.

Fuji Xerox Co., Ltd. - R&D HQ, Yokohama, Kanagawa, Japan

Researcher - Predictive Models

September, 2018 - October 2020

Responsibilities included researching long-term predictions in sequential recommender models and interpretability. Also worked on modeling missing patterns in observation health record data from the ICU, and designed algorithms which enabled early diagnosis of diseases.

Visiting Scholar - Affective Computing

September, 2017 - July, 2018

Worked on sentiment analysis models and their interpretability using NLP and reinforcement learning respectively. Also learned about orchestration frameworks for IoT devices.

Voonik Technologies Pvt. Ltd. - R&D, Bangalore, Karnataka, India

Research Intern

December, 2016 - June 2017

Worked on building a real-time recommendation system from scratch, primarily focusing on latency minimization and state-of-the-art algorithm reproduction. Successfully completed a system compatible with limited hardware, employing a graph-based algorithm and a Neo4j database. The project was successfully deployed for a user-base of 10,000 users.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS Massachusetts Institute of Technology - CSAIL

Student Project

March, 2016 - June 2016

Worked on a research project under Prof. P.H. Winston. Framed a doctor-patient conversation such that it may be used in a AGI system called "Genesis". Experiments were conducted to explore the system's feasibility in a clinical decision support setting for real time diagnosis. Conclusions drawn included confirming the system's feasibility for said task, with the limitation of a lack of medical-specific lexicon. The system's lexicon was expanded, showing improved inductive abilities.

SRM University - Dept. of Computer Science

Project Mecura

May, 2014 - May 2015

Initiated a project for developing a Electronic Medical Record-keeping System for the university hospital. Coordinated a team of 8 members to successfully design a website and back-end system for storing patient health record information for easy access. Learned full-stack development, privacy challenges in healthcare data and leadership skills.

PUBLICATIONS

Janmajay Singh, Masahiro Sato and Tomoko Ohkuma. 2021. On Missingness Features in Machine Learning Models for Critical Care: Observational Study. JMIR Medical Informatics (*JMI '21*).

Janmajay Singh, Oshiro Kentaro, Raghava Krishnan, Masahiro Sato, Tomoko Ohkuma and Noriji Kato. 2019. Utilizing Informative Missingness for Early Prediction of Sepsis. Computing in Cardiology Conference (*CinC* '19).

Masahiro Sato, **Janmajay Singh**, Sho Takemori, Takashi Sonoda, Qian Zhang and Tomoko Ohkuma. 2019. Uplift-based Evaluation and Optimization of Recommenders. ACM Conference on Recommender Systems (*Recsys '19*).

Masahiro Sato, **Janmajay Singh**, Sho Takemori, Takashi Sonoda, Qian Zhang and Tomoko Ohkuma. 2020. Modeling User Exposure with Recommendation Influence. ACM/SIGAPP Symposium On Applied Computing (SAC '20).

Sho Takemori, Masahiro Sato, Takashi Sonoda, **Janmajay Singh** and Tomoko Ohkuma. 2020. Submodular Bandit Problem Under Multiple Constraints. Proceedings of the 36th Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI '20)

Joachim Behar, Chengyu Liu, Kevin Kotzen, Kenta Tsutsui, Valentina Corino, **Janmajay Singh**, ..., Gari Clifford. 2020. Remote health diagnosis and monitoring in the time of COVID-19. Physiological Measurement, November 2020.

Under Review

Janmajay Singh, Naoko Yamaguchi, Masahiro Sato and Kengo Goto. BioForce: A REINFORCE-based Biomarker Selection Method for Early Cancer Diagnosis.

AWARDS

Outstanding Research Award: Twice (2020 and 2021) recipient, usually given to 10 of \sim 300 members of the R&D group.

Physionet Challenge 2019 Finished 5th of 104 teams internationally by building a highly accurate model for early diagnosis of sepsis in a population of ICU patients.

OTHER EDUCATION MITx - Statistics and Data Science MicroMasters, edx.org

An online Masters program hosted by MIT. The courses fulfill the MIT IDSS PhD credit requirements. 4/4 completed.

• 14.310Fx: Data Analysis in Social Science

• 6.86x: Machine Learning with Python

• 6.431x: Probability

• 18.6501x: Fundamentals of Statistics

Computer Skills

• Languages: Python, R, Java, C++, bash scripting.

• Databases and Tools: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Neo4j, Kafka